Hello friends, welcome to Tip Insights.
Today we are going to talk about
how to get pre-approval before surgery.
What is its process? Are
any documents required?
We are going to discuss all of that in this video.
In this video, we are going to
tell you what doubts you have in your mind
before getting pre-approval, whether you will get full coverage for the surgery or
not, what
documents are required for it, what is the
process, how do you go to the hospital,
what documents are required, there are
many doubts in your mind. The
biggest doubt
in case of surgery is whether my claim will be
approved or not. So
we will focus more on these doubts and
we are going to tell you many other things through this video.
So let's start the video
[Music]. I am going to
tell you why it is important to get pre-approval before surgery.
After getting pre-approval, we
cannot get it even by talking to a FinanciallyExpress agent.
Whenever a doctor tells us about any  If someone
asks for surgery, we get admitted to the hospital.
What happens in an emergency case is that we are not able to get pre-approval, so
we do not know whether
this thing is covered under our policy or
not. After getting admitted to the hospital,
when we process the request
through the TPA, the request is rejected or denied from there, so
what happens in that condition is that
we have to make that payment from our pocket,
so this is the biggest problem.
I am going to tell you now how important it is to get pre-approval in case of surgery. There are
some broad points in case of surgery
which I am going to tell you today. The
first point is that we have to consult a doctor.
When we have any problem
or we have any discomfort, then we
go to a doctor for treatment
and if the doctor feels that
surgery is required, then we have to
start the second process. The second
process is that we have to
contact our provider.
Provider means we will go from hospital to hospital.  There's a
TPA team there.
We'll talk to them.
After talking to them, we'll find out
what documents we need to attach, what
forms we need to sign,
and which forms we need to sign. The
TPA
team will explain the entire process to you. We can also find out about this
from our agent, online policy provider, or
customer service at the place where we purchased the policy.
What happens in the third point? When
we submit the documents to the TPA, the
TPA team gets us to sign a pre-
authorization form. The
patient's details are written in that form, including the
patient's medical
history, and any
diagnosis related to the treatment. The
hospital's name is mentioned on the
form, along with the hospital's signature stamp. The
patient
or the patient's attendant must sign it. The
fourth point is that
we have to attach some supporting documents.
First,  For documents, we have to
attach a copy of the policy or a
copy of the health card. Second, it will be his
ID. Third, the documents related to his treatment. If he has to undergo
surgery, then
what lab tests have he done, whether it is an
ultrasound, an X-ray, an
ECG, or a CT scan.
Whatever it is, all of them have to be attached in the supporting documents.
Before undergoing surgery, whatever
lab test we get done, an ultrasound, an
ECG, a CT
scan, etc., we
must mention that the
patient actually needs surgery. This is
very important because when the TPI
is processed, the documents are
forwarded to the insurance company. There is a
team of doctors there too,
they verify these documents.
After that, the further process starts. The
fifth point is when we give all the comments
to the TPA, give it to the TPA team and
submit it to the hospital. So,
what happens after that is that the hospital
team forwards the
documents to the insurance company.
All the documents are reviewed by the insurance company and it is
seen that
what was the waiting period of this policy, what was the waiting period of this surgery
and whether it is covered or not
and if it is covered then what is its limit
of surgery and this procedure also has a
limit, so the
insurance company checks all those things, it is the same
in the corporate as well, there is a
limit for everything in the corporate, there is a limit for every surgery,
so after reviewing everything the
insurance company gives approval or
rejects the claim,
after checking all those things the
insurance company decides,
after our documents are submitted to the insurance company either we get initial approval from there which is
called pre-approval or it gets
rejected, if the initial
approval comes then what we have to do in that case is
that we have to meet the doctor again
because there is some time period for that initial approval, that pre-
approval, it is two
days, four days, one week maximum or maximum up
to 10 days, during that period
we  Surgery is compulsory, so
after getting the initial approval, we have to
meet the doctor. The doctor decides a date for the
surgery and we have to get the
surgery done on that date. After getting the date from the doctor,
we can easily get the surgery done.
One thing to keep in mind is that the
initial approval, the pre-approval, has
many things mentioned in it like this much is
your payment, this much will be
your deduction, this much you have to pay
or your limit is this much, your room rent
limit is this much, so you have to check those things
very carefully because
suppose there is a surgery of Rs 50,000 and
he spent Rs 3000 in it, then it will be
mentioned in it that you have to pay Rs 20, it can be
different reasons, it is mentioned on it that due to
which reason you have to
pay this, so when the initial approval comes,
review it very carefully,
read it carefully and only after that get your patient
admitted in the hospital for surgery.  That's all for
today's video, we will meet
in the next video, till then
hello, please subscribe to our channel and
like the video, if you have any question
related to surgery or TP
or iron, write to us in the comment section,
we will answer you, till then
thank you so
much.